TALBOT FRENCH

Provo, Utah 84606 (817)995-0941
talbot.french@gmail.com
LinkedIn Github Portfolio

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with experience in creating well functioning programs, identifying errors, and a keen eye for creating visually pleasing front ends. Adaptive ability to custom design through multiple digital media programs (Photoshop, Illustrator) and well as vast communication skills to allow for cooperation on any team.

SKILLS

Languages: C#, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL

Frameworks: MVC / Entity

IDE: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code

Databases: SQL / MS SQL

Graphic Design: Photoshop, Illustrator

Team Share: Azure, TFS

SOFT SKILLS

Team player - Fluent in Spanish - Analytical thinker - Creative - Self Motivated

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Prosper IT | 2019 - Present

- -Team development project creating an MVC 5 through Azure in Visual Studio. Worked with other developers on a daily basis to create Multiple web pages using C#, .NET, MVC. MS SQL.
- -Took existing code and Stylized and edited Navbar Adding Icons and sub menus allowing for easy access to alternative web pages. Edited and improved overall style of the project adding to the presentability across application performance.
- -Developed PartialViews relating to button sets to ensure consistency and a solid appearance on front-end using HTML and CSS as well as efficiency by consolidating code and creating a reusable snippets on the backend through C#.

MISSION LEADER Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints | 2017 - 2019

- Lead teams of missionaries in their proselytizing efforts including establishing meetings and conducting training of ways to implement new techniques. Organized and directed community service projects in multiple provinces and worked with communities

to establish and execute youth outreach programs.

EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT

HRH French Bulldogs | 2012 - 2017

- Marketing and advertising assistant worked hand in hand with lead web developer and attended sales meeting as company representative

EDUCATION HISTORY

THE TECH ACADEMY Software Development

- Was trained in the use of multiple coding languages, and taught in depth to utilize them to create a variety of programs. The education included a foundation of technological terms and practices with a total of 600 hours of real experience and a formal introduction into the industry with an internship where a web MVC was developed to a professional grade along with a team of other developers.

NORTHWEST HIGH SCHOOL Graduated on Distinguished track

- TSA State award, Metal sculptures on 5 pounds - Captain, Ultimate Frisbee - Member, Varsity Football - Member, Varsity Track